No cells.
The best they had were satellite phones,
and in order to capture a satellite phone,
you had to fly directly over it.
On top of that, the only people
who had sat phones were the filthy rich...
the landowners, the politicians...
And lucky for us,
the narcos were richer than them all.
[phone squeaking]
[man speaking Spanish]
What's up, Lizard?
We're going out tonight.
[narrator] And once you got a signal,
you didn't know who you were listening to.
That's why back then, the US government
developed software that could identify
- the voices of our targets.
- [indistinct chatter on headphones]
I got Poison at 400 to 1700 megahertz,
gentlemen.
And you guessed it:
no GPS either.
Hammer, prepare to engage.
[narrator] Once we got a target,
we still had to locate it.
So we had to triangulate their signals
using assets on the ground.
[chatter in Spanish over headphones]
OK, he's in Modelia.